Andy Bool

Contact



07941 042227



andybooldev@gmail.com



AndyB0o1



Andy Bool



See my Portfolio

Full Stack Software Developer

I'm a passionate and enthusiastic software developer with an interest in both front and back-end development. At the end of 2022, having had a successful career in the charity sector, I decided I wanted a new challenge and career. So, I took the decision to take some time out to spend time with my family and decide where I wanted to go next.

Having worked with developers to create apps and web-based platforms to successfully engage people with conservation campaigns across the world, I have an enduring interest in software development and developing those skills for myself. Research and talking to relevant contacts and recruiters in the sector led me to securing a place on the iO Academy Software Development Bootcamp as a start to learning the relevant skills to build a new career in software development. Alongside the technical skills I learned on the course, having been the 'customer' will hopefully help me bring an added perspective to a developer role.

I still have a passion for conservation and am a volunteer trustee at a local Bird of Prey charity and enjoy spending my free time outside – walking or cycling and ideally birdwatching.

Developer skills

React
PHP
Laravel
JavaScript
HTML
CSS
Tailwind
GitHub collaboration

Other skills

Problem solving
Stakeholder Engagement
Teamworking
Requirement gathering
Organisational skills
Communication skills
Project Management

Professional Qualifications

iO Academy Software Development Bootcamp Graduate

May to August 2024

Level 5 Award in Leadership and Management, Institute of Leadership and Management

Nov 2012

Projects

I've recently graduated from the iO Academy Software Developer Essentials Bootcamp and during my time there worked on a number of projects, both as an individual, in a scrum team and pair-coding using GitHub for collaboration. Languages and frameworks I've used are: React, PHP, Laravel, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, MySQL, RESTful APIs and JavaScript. A couple of my favourite projects are linked below, for others, please see my <u>portfolio</u>.

Using React

Invoicing system

Using React with a provided API, we developed an invoicing system to match a required spec and design. I pair programmed the homepage showing all invoices and their status along with the number unpaid and the individual invoice page showing the full details of an invoice, using Tailwind for the styling.

Github | Live

Using Laravel

Book swap API

Using PHP, the Laravel framework and a supplied front-end this was a group project to develop an API for a book swap site. Following REST principles, I pair programmed a number of elements including appropriate unit tests: methods to view details of multiple and single books using genre and other filters and add reviews. We also mob programmed an admin level log in and dashboard view.

<u>Github</u> | <u>Live</u> | <u>API</u>

Career History

Dec 2022 to Present

Following a successful career in the charity sector, I decided I wanted a new challenge and career so I took this time to spend time with family and to research and decide on that new career. This resulted in me completing a software development bootcamp at iO Academy in Bath from May to August 2024.

Voluntary work

Trustee, Bird of Prey Project, Bath

May 2022 - Present

Chief Executive

Mammal Society, Bath

Nov 2021 to Dec 2022

Leader of a UK focused conservation charity. I developed and secured sign off from the Board for a 5 year plan for the organisation as well as leading a team of 5 to deliver projects and campaigns focused on protecting UK mammals. I worked with developers on maintenance and updates and additions to their Mammal Mapper app. The role enhanced my planning, teamworking and leadership skills.

Head of the SEA LIFE Trust

SEA LIFE Trust, Poole

Oct 2014 to Aug 2021

Leader of a global marine conservation charity. I was responsible for developing strategy and plans including the operating of two animal sanctuaries (in the UK and Iceland) and led a team of 45 to deliver against those plans and kept the organisation going through the COVID pandemic. In this role, I worked with developers to redesign and relaunch our website, create our beluga sanctuary website and bookings platform and on digital apps to encourage participation in our campaigns across the world. I further developed my leadership, teamworking, planning and budgeting skills.

Head of Fundraising

Marine Conservation Society, Ross on Wye
Aug 2010 to Oct 2014
Leader of a team of fundraisers for a UK marine conservation charity. In this role I
further developed my leadership, team working, negotiating, planning and budgeting
skills.

Fundraising Management roles

Various charities, UK

Mar 2000 to Aug 2010

During this period, bar a career break from Jun 2004 to Oct 2005 spent travelling around Central and South America, I worked for four charities – CancerBACUP, UNICEF UK, Hope and Homes for Children and Whale and Dolphin Conservation. My roles involved raising significant funds from companies, individuals and trusts and foundations to support the work of the charities. I developed strong communication, negotiating, networking, team working, planning and team leadership skills during this period.

Project Manager

Business to Business Exhibitions, London Dec 1995 to Mar 2000 Organising trade exhibitions in the UK and responsible for new business development for a small exhibition company. I learnt project management, time management, planning, budgeting, negotiating, team-working and team leadership skills in this role.

Oct 1988 to Dec 1995

During this period I did two years of a BSc(Hons) degree in Forestry before taking the decision to travel in SE Asia, Australia and Europe. I undertook various temporary roles (mostly admin/office based) along with a ski season in France to fund my travelling.

Education

1988 3 A levels - Geography, Geology and Biology, Bilborough College, Nottingham

1985 8 O levels – Maths, Chemistry, Physics, Biology, Geography, Eng Lang, Eng Lit and French, Alderman White Comprehensive, Nottingham